<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/tag/nietzsche/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2024-05-05T15:29:50-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/tag/nietzsche/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Hanleyjames.github.io | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>A blog about software engineering and books</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">New Years and Re-reading Nietzsche</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/new-years-nietzsche" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Years and Re-reading Nietzsche" />
      <published>2023-12-30T04:00:00-07:00</published>
      <updated>2023-12-30T04:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/new-years-nietzsche</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/new-years-nietzsche">&lt;p&gt;Happy New Years everyone,
I wanted to lay out a general goal for me and re-read through some of the Kaufmann translations of Nietzsche. I had seen some newer distaste for Nietzsche arise and realize it has been close to a decade since I read his works. I am going to start with Thus Spoke and read through the others in chronological order. I would like to afterwords spend some time reading and exploring newer academic critiques of his works. I feel like a lot has changed in 10 years, including peoples attitudes towards Nietzsche.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>James Hanley</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Nietzsche" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Happy New Years everyone, I wanted to lay out a general goal for me and re-read through some of the Kaufmann translations of Nietzsche. I had seen some newer distaste for Nietzsche arise and realize it has been close to a decade since I read his works. I am going to start with Thus Spoke and read through the others in chronological order. I would like to afterwords spend some time reading and exploring newer academic critiques of his works. I feel like a lot has changed in 10 years, including peoples attitudes towards Nietzsche.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
