<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>A blog about software engineering and books</description>
    <link>
    http://localhost:4000</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>JS Malware Obsfucation</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been spending my free time recently learning how Javascript malware works, and what are some common methods for infection. While this might be something others know or have touched upon, for me this is all new. My knowledge of JS Malware in recent memory really only dealt with cryptomining. Some of the things that I am coming to learn is the majority will focus on windows machines. Primarily (I don’t have enough experience to say this with confidence), they use &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/previous-versions/windows/it-pro/windows-server-2003/cc738350(v=ws.10)&quot;&gt;Windows Script Host/WSH&lt;/a&gt; to do the majority of the work. Either from there they use WSH or &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/previous-versions/windows/desktop/automat/activex-objects&quot;&gt;ActiveXObjects&lt;/a&gt; to write files. I am not really sure which ones are examples of those that effect unix based systems that are not either hijacked node packages, or&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 05:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/js-malware-Obsfucation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/js-malware-Obsfucation</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>New Years and Re-reading Nietzsche</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Years everyone,
I wanted to lay out a general goal for me and re-read through some of the Kaufmann translations of Nietzsche. I had seen some newer distaste for Nietzsche arise and realize it has been close to a decade since I read his works. I am going to start with Thus Spoke and read through the others in chronological order. I would like to afterwords spend some time reading and exploring newer academic critiques of his works. I feel like a lot has changed in 10 years, including peoples attitudes towards Nietzsche.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/new-years-nietzsche</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/new-years-nietzsche</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Interesting features of Power Automate Custom Connectors</title>
        
          <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;interesting-features-of-power-automate-custom-connectors&quot;&gt;Interesting features of Power Automate Custom Connectors&lt;/h2&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 03:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/welcome</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/welcome</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
